Nahida Islam







www.linkedin.com/in/nahida-islam/ in



Highly motivated IT professional with experience working on several different projects and applications, during a 5-year IT education at KTH. I like to meet customer requirements with innovative solutions that maximize efficiency and exceed capability targets. I have a great passion for learning new things, and it is important for me to continuously develop my skills and grow as a developer as well as a designer. I want to be a part of a team that is working together and contribute to the company's future. I have a great interest in sustainability and open to work with companies who values sustainability.

For more examples of projects in detail, visit my portfolio.

For some examples of programming projects and applications I have worked on, visit my <u>Github</u>.

Professional Experiences

2021 - CURRENT

Software Engineer/Frontend/ Acast

Working as a frontend developer at Acast. The purpose of the unit is to enable content creators to monetize and advertisers to reach the right audience at scale. The main framework used on the frontend is React.Js.

2020 - 2020

Video Encoder (short-term)/ Postnord

Working independently to ensure that letters / packages reach the right person by sorting them via different computer systems and the required sorting rules. The work requires a high demand on focus and accuracy throughout the work shifts.

2016 - 2020

1st line NOC-Operator/Teracom AB

Problem-solving and customer contact are two lead words for this role. Teracom broadcasts TV and radio in Sweden and supplies data services. The role of a NOC operator includes monitoring of networks, troubleshooting, and dispatch for service business. The work requires an eye for accuracy and planning as well as the ability to make quick decisions under pressured situations.

JAN 2020 - JUN 2020

Master's thesis/ CERO

An user-centered evaluation of the CERO simulation tool. The work includes interviweing customers, prototyping a potential design and lastly testing the produced design. During this work I experienced the whole cycle of UX design.

The thesis report can be viewed in Diva KTH: Thesis report

Group leader/ Teklafestival (KTH)

A group of students was assigned to me. My job was to navigate the group to different places and perform fun tasks with them. This gave me a good insight into leading a group.

2014 - 2014

Preschool teacher/Sätra Förskolan

A summer job where I worked with children from 2 years to 5 years old.

Competencies

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

- HTML CSS & JAVASCRIPT
- REACT.JS, Gatsby

PROTOTYPING TOOLS

- Figma
- Sketch
- Adobe XD
- Adobe illustrator

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- JAVA
- C, C#
- QUERY LANGUAGE: XQUERY

OTHER COMPETENCIES

- UNITY 3D
- BLENDER
- MICROSOFT ACCESS, DATABASE MANAGEMENT
- DIA, ASTAH, XQUISITOR
- MYSQL

OPERATIVE SYSTEM

- WINDOWS 7 WINDOWS 10
- LINUX (KUBUNTU)

Education

2014-2020

Degree programme in Information and Communication Technology/ Royal Institute of Technology

The education provided a broad knowledge in IT. I have taken courses in various technical areas such as software programming, web development, human-computer interaction, graphics and UX design.

Languages

BENGALI MOTHER TONGUE.

SWEDISH VERY GOOD KNOWLEDGE IN WRITTEN AND SPOKEN.

ENGLISH VERY GOOD KNOWLEDGE IN WRITTEN AND SPOKEN.

HINDI GOOD KNOWLEDGE IN SPOKEN ONLY.

URDU GOOD KNOWLEDGE IN SPOKEN ONLY.

Driving license

Driving license B 2018